Trevor Kelly

★ trevork.dev trevor.daniel.kelly@gmail.com TrevorDKelly Pittsburgh, PA

Profile

I am a software engineer with multiple years of experience in JavaScript (ES6), Ruby, Go, and multiple frameworks. I am a co-creator of Chimera \mathscr{D} , which automates canary deployments for containerized microservices that communicate via a service mesh on AWS.

Experience

Co-Creator, Software Engineer, Chimera - https://chimera-deploy.dev *∂*

2022 - present Remote

- Researched, designed, prototyped, and implemented Chimera, an open-source tool for performing automated canary deployments of containerized microservices
- Automated a deployment process that involves manipulating multiple AWS services concurrently
- Configured CloudWatch and Prometheus to monitor traffic flowing through a newly released microservice
- Automated the rollback process based off of production metrics data
- Utilized AWS's Software Development Kit to interact with and manipulate cloud infrastructure
- Created server-sent events stream to pass live updates and metrics data charts to a user interface
- Built a production microservice system for development testing
- Designed workflow and infrastructure diagrams.
- Collaborated with a remote team spread across four different cities
- Authored a comprehensive technical case study documenting design decisions
- Presented a live tech talk describing the project

Software Engineer, *Self-Employed*

2019 - 2022

• Monkeys Typing Hamlet - Monkey hands randomly typing on a keyboard, tracking whether they type *Hamlet*

Remote

- Google Cloud VPS hosted, NGINX reverse proxy, and Node express app with MongoDB and Redis
- Requestotron Webhook and HTTP request visualizer for viewing and debugging network communication
 - Node express app with PostgreSQL and MongoDB databases
- DOM-Keyboard In-browser interactive keyboard built out of DOM nodes and released as an npm package
 - Zero dependency Javascript using promise syntax for chain-able method calls with OOP design

Operations Manager, Castleview Partners

2016 - 2020

Independent financial advisory firm for high-net-worth individuals

Chicago

- Transitioned two advisors, over 50 clients, and over 300 accounts to the firm.
- Organized account set up and management for clients, custodial firms, and private investment companies.

Skills

Languages	Frameworks	Technologies	Cloud
Javascript, ES6, Ruby, Go,	Express, Sinatra,	Git, GitHub, Docker,	AWS: ECS, ECR, Fargate,
SQL, HTML, CSS	React/Redux, Node,	CI/CD, HTTP, REST APIs,	App Mesh, CloudWatch
	Handlebars, jQuery	NGINX, Redis, MongoDB	Google Cloud VPS

Education

Launch School, Software Engineering

2019 - 2022

Multi-year, mastery-based software engineering curriculum with progression gated by written exams and live coding interviews to develop problem-solving skills. LaunchSchool.com/employers &

Westfield State University, BA in Communications

2008 - 2012